Morevna Project presents
Hello Master! - Hello! - Where are we going today?
Hello, my name is Konstantin Dmitriev.
I am production manager of "Pepper & Carrot" motion comic
which is based on a comic by David Revoy
In this video I invite you
to plunge into the atmosphere of our studio, where we
all work together
Today we all gathered in the studio
to discuss current production issues
and what tasks we are facing
"I would like eight pumpkin stars, please."
"Here you are! That's sixty Ko."
Yes! Yes!
I am missing more action here... To show how much it all difficult for her...
Maybe add extra scene, at least one there...
In all other aspects I like everything. And the rhythm too...
That's it, Carrot! I think, I have everything I need.
And then we can make a zoom out. Yes.
And do transition through changing opacity... Yes.
Then, this will be one task - to draw Pepper and a closeup of the udder.
By the way, I don't like the tail here. This bump on the tail.
That was in original? - No, I did it...
Well, how about to make it like dragon's tail?
Today our teenager students also came
to our studio.
Some of them help us with production of motion comic.
They are helping us to prepare artwork
for other episodes,
which we plan to launch in the future.
We prepare artwork for animation.
That means separating characters and objects
from background.
So, you finished this one? - Yes, I did.
Now, the next frame,
first of all, you should save it under a different name.
And, of course, the guys don't forget to take a break,
to have a rest from the hard and exhausting work of the animator.
Well, that's all!
As usual, you can track our progress
by subscribing to us on social media.
See all relevant links in the description of this video.
We will continue showing our work process
on the motion comic "Pepper & Carrot".
Thank you for watching and see you next time! Goodbye!
Well, that's all!
As usual, you can track our progress...
Thank you! Thank you...